[Music]
[Applause]
readings and salutations this is abe
abdelhadi with the bitter truth where we
may not have all the answers but we're
going to ask an awful lot of questions
you can also help the show out by
visiting the bitter truth dot
info info and there you could buy some
fabulous swag to make your life better
or support us on the patreon link that's
there
uh so it's nice to have people support
the show these things can be heard on
spotify itunes youtube all the usual
suspects
at no charge but the support is always
appreciated today i'm excited to have a
a guest a friend of the show been on
before former cia counter
counter terrorist chief in pakistan and
the first whistleblower
that obama put in the joint back in the
day and what was funny because he blew
the whistle on the
bush administration and he didn't even
give anybody anything he just said some
stuff on the news
uh john karachi how are you man hey very
well thanks thanks for having me back
gabe
hey man thanks for coming on so um some
some uh some
it sounds like you got some legal
victories before you jump into the main
thing what's going on
yeah you know it's it's it's a slog but
uh over the course
of the last you know
13 years uh i've had my detractors and
in some cases these detractors
went too far and uh you know i've
connected with some
really amazing attorneys over the last
few years
people like you know harvard law
professors and georgetown law professors
and now after being reactive
and responsive for the last decade i'm
going to start going after people
i wish i could go into more detail
things are turning around and i'm i'm
very excited about it i appreciate the
generosity even saying anything at all
and
number one number two good for you
because you i i followed you before we
even
met cyber cyber spacey or whatever you
want to call it but um
yeah i've always admired you and i
thought you know you're you're
principled guy that
yeah i i don't know if i would have
taken what you took even even the 23
months i would have probably hung myself
and you know just as an aside in
august um i was offered a job
that was like like the job dropped out
of heaven into my lap
and it was my big comeback i was going
to be the chief
operating officer of a private equity
firm
based in athens uh i'm a dual us
greek citizen now and um
it was more money than i could ever have
dreamt of
i gladly took the job and then
you know six weeks into it i realized
this is a money laundering operation
and so i had to resign and i had to call
the fbi
and yeah you know it's always something
doing something man i get it i get it um
well hey man listen uh you know i know
we uh we gotta we got a little bit of
time
um before you gotta take off yourself um
now now you you're no longer doing loud
and clear with uh brian becker right you
guys uh
yeah i'm no longer doing loud and clear
with brian becker um that was such a
wonderful show
and i have such deep respect for brian
even if we don't
agree on everything politically he's
such a he's such a
good kind good-hearted person
i i learned a lot from him uh but the
show ran its course
uh it was uh you know the contract was
up
is what it was so we all left they shut
the show down
uh sometime in at the end of august i
think it was
uh i went into the private sector as i
just said that didn't work out i
called sputnik back and said hey uh
i wouldn't mind having another show and
yeah so they
they put me on in the same time slot
four to six pm with lee stranahan
good for you and what's that show called
that's called the back story
the backstory good times all right i'll
put that in the uh it's much less
newsy it's uh it's a lot of
um how can i say it it's
it's two guys drinking a beer
uh just talking about the day yeah yeah
and and mostly it's much more newsy
yeah and that's i i i when i first
started this almost three years ago and
i just didn't want it
i mean obviously i'm going to talk about
current events and this than the other
but i want it to be more evergreen
where like if people go back and hear a
show with you or mikko palette or
somebody
yes regardless of when they hear it they
go oh man that's
oh i didn't know that right as opposed
to oh yeah well this already happened
and he already went to jail for that or
whatever
um and and then plus because i'm only on
a couple of days a week anyway so i
don't want it i didn't want it to be so
um so newsy you know but uh speaking of
evergreen topics
uh i guess we could talk about uh april
haynes
who is the uh new biden director of
national intelligence and she seems
like the rest of this cabinet like a
nice prize what's uh i was very
very disappointed yeah and remember she
was
the first biden national security
appointee
right so avril avril actually doesn't
have a long history in intelligence
but the history that she has is dark
right she
um she was up on the hill when biden was
on the hill
biden took her to the white house when
he became vice president
she and tony blinken both right and um
and avril became the general counsel for
the national security council now
in that position she was working
directly for john brennan
dangerous in and of itself i would say
your your old buddy
my old buddy john brennan yeah
that's that's a whole other topic a
whole nother we've talked about it so
yeah
so um you know john was responsible for
the kill list right which was a list of
people
that he would come up with every tuesday
who were to be
killed uh that week with usually with a
drone sometimes with a hit squad that
the agency would send out
right and so avril was the lawyer
who approved the uh the kill list
and there are press reports
uh saying that and i mean like
legitimate press reports from the post
and the times in the journal and places
like that
saying that that arrow frequently would
take a call in the middle of the night
saying we've got the guy in our sights
request permission to launch
and it was avril who gave permission to
launch wow and uh you know she was so
good at that job
that when john became cia director he
took avril with him
and um and she was the uh the deputy
director of the cia
and there she didn't even really tackle
any of this any of these things she just
kind of went after hacks and leaking
right
that was it and you know that's very
much a john brennan thing to do
right john brennan was known for having
a nixonian
obsession with national security leagues
so that's what she did now another thing
that avril did that bothers me very much
is that um it was avril who gave
the the legal um justification
for cia officers breaking into the
senate intelligence committee's computer
system
to to try to spy on the investigators
there to see what they were
collecting uh in the run-up to the to
the completion of the torture report
uh dianne feinstein referred that to
the justice department for prosecution
it was never
taken up never even investigated wow and
um
and she got away with it right but she
never had to answer questions about the
kill list
she never had to answer questions about
breaking into this the senate
intelligence committee's computer system
right never see and and to your point
that
you know you know you mentioned blinking
earlier uh he is another one you know
the biden pretty much gave his entire
career and then when i watched
uh your career it's gentile and then
when i watched part of his uh
confirmation hearing i was blown away
you know that that phrase i stopped
clock until the time right twice a day i
was
shocked that rand paul a actually had a
spine
to say anything and then the things that
he went after him for
because other republicans didn't even
ask those kinds of questions
and it just seems like this kind of [__]
just gets rewarded where like you know
guys like you or snowden or assange you
get punished
we get punished and the reason why even
republicans didn't challenge tony
blanken in his confirmation hearing
is that there is no difference between a
neo-liberal foreign policy and a
neoconservative foreign policy
it's interventionist no matter who's in
the white house
that foreign policy is interventionist
you said correctly
that tony blinken owes his entire career
to joe biden
i knew tony when i was up on the uh on
the senate uh foreign relations
committee
i even took his desk when when he
finally went to the white house
um but he started off as a junior staff
member
right joe biden right for years he
worked in biden's uh personal office
in the senate and then he worked his way
up through the ranks in the senate uh
foreign relations committee when biden
was the chairman he became the staff
director
then he became uh briefly biden's
national security advisor as vice
president and then deputy national
security advisor
so the guy's been around you know
forever right
forever and he parrots
the biden neoliberal foreign policy i
mean what's the first foreign policy
thing joe biden did
literally on his first day as president
he sent additional troops to syria
oh and and on the same day doubled down
on venezuela with the 30 million
the 30 million that trump left in the uh
last
uh covet bill yes we dedicated 30
million to
coup venezuela again and joe biden just
vowed to double down on venezuela
recognizing juan guado as the interim
president
i think it's down to what three
countries now that recognize them israel
us and i think you know
malaysia or some [__] like there's no
credible governments
that you know what i mean like there's
nobody recognizing this
and he ain't got any him in his entire
faction got voted out of office in
december
yeah even his own supporters don't
recognize him anymore
right so like why are we still like
pimping this dead horse and and saying
it runs it's just
and he's under investigation by the fbi
for for hacking 90 million or ganking 90
million dollars
out of the money he out of the moneys he
was given it's like
this is exactly what ahmed chalabi did
when we decided that he was going to be
the president of iraq that's right next
thing you know 60 million dollars in cia
money is missing
that's right you know that's right let
me ask you something because
it just seems like you said it a second
ago it's intervention it doesn't mean it
doesn't matter if it's
it's just neo you know we should just we
should make up our own term called neo
interventionists because
whether they're whether they like gay
people or don't like gay people the one
thing they do like to do is invade other
countries and take their [__] for free
that's right and we just got lloyd
austin a general
yes who mattis was a general and he's
also a former
a former raytheon guy who you took the
words right out of my mouth yeah
you took the words right out of my mouth
he's a four-star general and a raytheon
lobbyist
yeah and guess what he's like the third
one in a row
who's been a defense industry lobbyist
right
defense yeah and there's nobody else in
america not qualified to be the
secretary of defense
and and and had to get a waiver like
mattis had to get a waiver and had to
get a waiver because we put the stop on
that [__] 1948 and eisenhower had to get
away
but he you know but still just those are
only three guys in history
that had to get a waiver since 1948 to
actually be a former
military guy to run for office or be
appointed in a cabinet
that's actually quite important to me
you know people used to ask me all the
time
especially when uh petraeus was the
director of
cia what my thoughts were on having
generals run the cia well i'm opposed to
generals running the cia
the odni dod i'm opposed to generals in
any of these national security positions
national security advisor for the very
simple reason
that generals became generals
by saying yes sir that's right right
what you need in a position like that is
somebody who can say mr president let me
tell you why that's a terrible idea
right and stand up generals don't stand
up
right not to the commander-in-chief they
don't
no they don't they say yes sir yeah so
we don't want generals in positions like
that
yeah yeah now you're making i mean and
then and i just watched doctor
strangelove again last night because i
haven't seen i haven't seen it
on netflix right now it's awesome yeah i
i caught it on amazon i was just like oh
my god i'm excited
i let my dvd with the bonus dvd and it
with kubrick and
i never got it back so i a long story
but
but um but you know but the george c
scott character in there is exactly like
what you're saying
yes he's just nervously chewing gum and
the president's asking these questions
he can't answer
because clearly somebody [__] up well
isn't it true then if i have the chain
of command then i'm suppo then i'm
supposed to
you know authorize nuclear weapons well
that's right sir
well then why didn't that happen like it
was like who's on first
but with nukes yes and it just seems
like
and then you know but kind of back to
haines um
because this is kind of my theory i mean
you know i can't prove it because that
hasn't happened yet but you know without
with a with a kamala
with the kamala harris presidency which
let's be honest if
if biden's not drooling into a rubber
diaper by summer i'll be shocked and i
am taking bets i might lose some money
yes
i've said the same thing yeah he's gonna
he's he's off but so
she comes in and and and it just seems
to me like these are the machinations of
turning the doj into a modern-day stasi
right where where this time it's
willingly because we give our
information to for for
for we put our face on avatars we you
know
amazon has a contract bozo and hamilton
has a surveillance contract
uh you know we you know google has a
contract with the cia nsa
so does twitter so does facebook um how
bad do you think it could possibly be
because
democrats are going to go to sleep the
so-called liberal in this country is
going to go to sleep under harris
administration
oh my god yes where do you even start
first of all
kamala harris is no liberal she is no
progressive
remember this is a woman who spent most
of her career as a prosecutor
yep and imagine how many lives she
ruined how many families she ruined by
seeking
the longest possible sentence for
first-time non-violent drug offenses
so let's not pretend that she's some
enlightened liberal she's not
secondly uh yeah i mean it's like every
every president or would-be president
wants to put his or her uh uh
personal stamp on foreign policy and how
do you do that
other than sending troops somewhere look
at barack obama who was supposed to be
the great
liberal savior right right and he put us
in
oh he kept us in iraq and afghanistan he
put us in somalia
in libya in syria in yemen in
countless uh saharan and sub-saharan
countries we're not even really
sure what all of our special forces
troops are doing in those countries
right so i i would expect more of
exactly the same
from president biden or uh
president uh harris yeah and there's no
reason to think that
anything would change see and this is
why this is what frustrates me i live in
austin texas right and
and the big crack they always make is
well yeah you was like california you're
still loop
yeah we're like california we got a
bunch of [__] chewy blue people
that's what i call them
i have i have like four friends that
think like you and i do right
and and and meaning like some of them
are you know lean a little bit on the
right side but they at least think and
they don't start calling you names just
because you don't agree with them that's
you know
like like my friends that voted for
trump you know they're not
like the classic trumper people right
and my friends that you know and then i
got friends that are more like
like me they think both sides are
corrupt both sides are full of [__] and
you just
like insist on having your spirit animal
yeah and get mad when i punch your teddy
bear
so but that's the challenge i have with
what's going on is this
this cabinet is almost identical resume
wise
to the trump cabinet oh oh yeah totally
totally the only place where i'm just
slightly
optimistic is merrick garland um
because he's he's not really a political
animal
right and so i'm slightly optimistic
that he'll be able to keep doj
independent but when it comes to well
you
a minute ago you raised the issue of
surveillance state surveillance
if if you could spend a month
in london oh my god you'll see state
surveillance oh yeah
it's ridiculous they're the most
surveilled country in the world
right the uk is yeah well we're we're
headed
right for that sure we're going to have
cameras everywhere we already have
cameras everywhere
how do you think so many people from the
capitol riots
were arrested so quickly it was because
of facial recognition software
absolutely wasn't just people ratting
them out from seeing their pictures on
facebook
right it was facial recognition software
all the feds had to do
was take stills from the videos that we
saw from the news
and feed it into their their facial
recognition database
remember they have our pictures from
driver's licenses
they have our pictures from facebook and
from google
and from youtube and tick tock and it's
easy to figure out who people are
absolutely essentially just give them
the information we give them the info we
just
the stasi whoever anastasia back in the
day is probably spinning his grave right
now if he knew it would be this easy
yeah seriously instead of going 1984
he'd have gotten brave new world no no
no no
let me give this vibrator that's gonna
take your picture at the same time here
have it and people
would have bought it right and you don't
even have to pay people you don't have
to pay sources we put all the
information out there
on ourselves that's right that's right
what facebook did i remember when it
came out and i got talked into getting
on it a good friend of mine talked to
tried talking and i wasn't a very social
media person
and it was remember when not myspace was
the big deal sure
and it was such a pain in the ass to use
like if somebody liked you you had to go
through this act of congress to accept
them
or if you went to go like them or or add
them as a friend it was like
you know are you you know it was just it
was a pain in the ass i think i had like
10 friends i didn't care and then my
friend said no no you gotta try this
it's easier it's better to
all it was was it was easier for
facebook to take
our info yes that's all it was and they
and they sell it
and remember they facebook doesn't give
us the platform
out of the goodness of their hearts they
monetize our personal data
right yeah i'll give you another example
too because they go farther than they
even admit to
i mean they'll come out and and admit it
if you ask them
in front of a congressional panel but uh
um i've gone through periods where i've
gotten a lot of threats
right if i if i go on tv i go on fox
news or i go on msnbc or whatever
i get threats right there are a lot of
crazy people out there that's right
that's right so i was talking to a buddy
of mine on the phone
who happens to be a firearms instructor
and he said
um he said have you ever had a concealed
carry permit and i say
yeah i had a concealed carry until 2012
but then you know i have a felony
conviction now so i
i can't own a gun anymore that's why i
need a pardon
well it's one of the reasons why i need
a party oh yeah countries and uh he said
yeah it's too bad you can't carry a gun
and you know we ended our conversation
five minutes later i go onto facebook
and
every single ad in my facebook feed is
for a concealed carry class
every single ad oh yeah so they're even
listening on the phone
oh they're listening when your phone is
turned off i play in a in a band out
here in town right
saturday nights we jam and you know
we're like a cover band we play we play
like rage against the machine and [__]
like that and get drunk
and so one night we're in practice and
my phone is usually on sleep
and we're talking about a base that i
used to have it was a fender jazz bass
it was a 1980 cream color tortoiseshell
pickguard
bitchin base next day i wake up
turn on my facebook and i got five
different ads
with people playing that base that
specific base with a specific color
scheme
one girl's like giving lessons on this
base you know and i'm going isn't that
interesting how that base came up and i
was just talking about it last night
i must have had eight or nine in a row
with your phone in sleep mode my phone
was in sleep mode
this is why when people say you know oh
my god i'm so paranoid of um
you know i'm like i i if i'm dating
somebody you know and let's just be
candid sometimes you send pictures back
and forth because that's what people who
date do
and then she could say oh my god what if
they're going to see it i go oh count on
it they are seeing it
they've already seen it let's give the
poor guys in the van a good show that's
what i say
and i'm a half decent writer so so the
fiction is just you know is is
penthouse form level material for weeks
knock yourselves out boys
that's my that's my taxpayer
contribution to your cause to your
entertainment
because we're i'm not you're online i'm
online we have a show
you know whatever i mean it's it doesn't
matter how many viewers you got or don't
have it's like it's you're you're
putting yourself out there
they track you with algorithms and
everything else and i'm also getting to
this sinister point where i'm
not trusting certain people based on
their language and i'm sure you've been
there for a while
you know yeah you can't imagine
the the emails and calls i get from
people who want to
offer me a job and the job
is always it's it's consulting and it's
always just
baiting me to to violate federal law
right to get you in trouble to keep you
from your case moving forward and
getting
your just desserts actually it happens
all the time yeah yeah
and and and that and seeing and you know
we got a few a couple more minutes
before i
have to start wrapping up but um you
know earlier you mentioned
uh uh john brennan it just seems
that it just seems that for at least the
last 70 years
regard i mean foreign policy is domestic
policy to me
because we spend two thirds of our
budget on military
not defense but military more than the
next eight largest
countries combined combined and if we
and if we cut down to 300 billion a year
we'd still be able to we don't need to
buy more weapons
we could just maintain but it just seems
like no matter who's in office
it just it's just the same [__] over
and over and they just dress it up
different
you know they're gonna dress up uh china
now and you know that we've had ships in
the south china sea now for what eight
or nine months
right floating around because because
why we're concerned about asia
yeah because because we're concerned
about it uh uyghurs we've been bombing
real muslims for 20 you know it doesn't
mean these people aren't muslims but
we've been bombing muslim muslims for 20
years now we're concerned about chinese
muslims
yeah right we just want their oil and
natural gas because they've been pulling
out of there for three years
in their own backyard yes but it but
people go on the party thing and if you
say
what i just said that biden harris won't
be any different than trump
uh pence they get really angry
and the sad truth is and i say this as a
former third generation democrat i'm no
longer a democrat
but the sad truth is that the trump
foreign
policy was more traditionally democratic
than the obama biden foreign policy oh
absolutely 100
well that's why they had to keep coming
up with crap like like russians paying
to kill
soldiers because every time you try to
pull back a little bit and use it he was
a chicken [__] as a human being anyway
but anytime you try to pull back the
slightest bit something that made him
unlikable would pop out and he would
freak out
and reverse course you know what i mean
and it's just it just doesn't seem like
it's ever going to go away i mean you
know people ask me all the time you know
well how do you think it's going to have
to how do you think the change is going
to come how do you think the change is
going to come
right uh you know what i'm not sure that
in the near tor
the in the near term change will come i
think that donald trump did such
a good job at energizing mainstream
democrats
that and so many people came out to vote
like we had such ridiculously
high voter turnout by american standards
that i think this neoliberal
interventionist foreign policy
uh has been cemented in the mainstream
yeah you know when for example aid
when biden sent these troops to syria on
january the 20th
did it even make the the media i mean i
had to look for the information i had
it wasn't in the washington post it
wasn't in the new york times because i
read them
cover to cover every every day nope but
uh
it's it's nobody really cares nobody
cares and
when you say and when you say anything
it's it's kind of like what nixon had
intended came true
get rid of the draft quit drafting
middle class white kids
yeah no one's going to give a [__] and
this and that's my friends here my
liberal friends here that are like well
you know bolivia he was there 14 years
that was a long time
well angela merkel ran germany for 15
years how come we didn't pull a coup in
germany
that's right you know it was because she
was white and then when you say well i
don't want i don't want to send kids of
oblivion like yeah well [__] i don't
care well
you don't care because you don't have a
kid in service you don't care because it
wasn't your kid got bombed
in an apartment building by us you know
just this lack of empathy and as long as
you're
i know we're short on time but you know
i said this internet you just you just
triggered something yeah
i just said this in an interview the
other day one of the things that i
learned
when i was the chief of counterterrorism
operations in pakistan after 9 11
is that all of the low-level al-qaeda
fighters i
i was responsible for capturing and
there were many
dozens of them right they all said the
same thing they all told the same story
and the story was that they had grown up
in some isolated village
in their home country whatever it was
yemen
saudi arabia algeria whatever they
had um no job prospects they had no
they had no uh job skills they were
illiterate
no man would want their daughter his
daughter to marry somebody like this
right because you know why why would you
the guy can't read and write he's got no
job skills
so the local imam went to them and said
hey what are you doing in this village
you should go to afghanistan and make
jihad against the americans
right we'll give you 500 a month and
then if you're martyred we'll give your
family a 500
martyrdom bonus right so they went they
went to afghanistan
they didn't read the quran they didn't
even know the prayers
they didn't have any beef against the
united states until we bombed their
village
right until we killed their cousin or
their brother or their grandfather or
whatever it was
that's right and then they decided they
were up for the fight
that's right that's right and and and
you know that and that is
that is exactly the point and that is
exactly the goal that has been achieved
here
i mean especially when you look at
afghanistan that was true up until
carter
a traditional a traditionally pretty
passive bunch of people they weren't
involved in you know except for except
for uh overturning the the ottoman
empire which everybody was
was fighting those guys you know in
world war one i mean they had
for 67 years they weren't doing anything
and that's what and to your point that's
what is so frustrating is that people
just
people will just look sideways as long
as it does not affect them
absolutely right and even even the crime
bill i mean i
i was i i lost quite a few black friends
of mine that i knew for a long time one
guy i knew 15 years called me left a
voicemail threatening to kick my ass
like that
because i'm going dude because i asked
him online do you not know what the
crime bill is and he got mad at me
i don't give a [__] about the crime i
want to trump out of there go do you
know what the crime bill is tell me and
then
i'll just accept your philosophy but
christ it's like you know it's just
ridiculous but
listen man um i know you gotta get going
um again thank you for your time
appreciate it good luck with the new
show
and uh get folks my uh my guest is
i appreciate you hey man as all i just
i'm i'm tickled anytime
you say you're gonna come on because
you're you're just a super smarty pants
guy so i like that
thank you folks um i guess it's been
john kiriakou and uh
hopefully you heard some stuff that made
a lot of sense and if it didn't i don't
give a [__]
uh there's because that's why it's
called facts versus opinion
and if this stuff makes you
uncomfortable it's supposed to sleep
[Applause]
[Music]
tight
in the city